<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress.com" created="2011-12-04 15:04"-->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.1/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.1/"
>

<channel>
	<title>S(e)oul eXchange</title>
	<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>One blue-eyed boy in a sea of rice, kimchi, K-POP and mobile phones.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 15:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.1</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://wordpress.com/</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>9130441</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>swaycz</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>honza@egoistic.biz</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[honza]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='soulexchange.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>S(e)oul eXchange</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>

	<item>
		<title>You know you are in Tokyo when...</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/01/you-know-you-are-in-tokyo-when/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 15:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=268</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<strong>...the banner at the airport says "Welcome to Japan"</strong> (well, technically, this only means that you came to Japan, but whatever)

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/01/you-know-you-are-in-tokyo-when/p1000965/" rel="attachment wp-att-277"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-277" title="Welcome to Japan" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/p1000965.jpg?w=530" alt="Welcome to Japan" width="530" height="306" /></a>

<strong>...a panda in a cape tells you not to put your hands into the doors</strong>

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/01/you-know-you-are-in-tokyo-when/p1000994/" rel="attachment wp-att-276"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-276" title="Poor crying panda" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/p10009941.jpg?w=530" alt="Poor crying panda" width="530" height="287" /></a>

<strong>...talking on the phone in the subway is highly discouraged.</strong> It is not prohibited, but they politely ask you to <em>"refrain from talking on your mobile phone"</em>. I would not risk a ninja cutting my ear...

<strong>...the subway system map is one big clusterfuck</strong>. Seriously, that shit does not make sense! While normal subway maps try to at least partially display the real layout, in Tokyo, it is neatly arranged without much connection to reality (OK, not entirely, but it is just laid out in a weird manner). The problem is also the duality of the transport system there. Firstly, there are the <del>Subway</del> Tokyo Metro and Toei, which represent the (mostly) underground parts. Secondly, there is the JR East part, which is a combination of regular trains (even Shinkansen) and commuter trains. These two parts can be used for transport in Tokyo, and in many cases you can transfer between subway and JR, but the maps quite often show either the JR or the subway system. At least they announce the other lines in the train's PA as well.

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="Tokyo Subway Map (i.e. without JR commuter trains) (source: http://picturetokyo.com)"]<img class=" " title="Tokyo Subway Map" src="http://picturetokyo.com/images/TokyoSubwayMap.gif" alt="Tokyo Subway Map" width="530" />[/caption]

<strong>...everything is more expensive than in Seoul. </strong>I knew that it is going to be expensive, but still, you are unpleasantly surprised when you find out that is really is. Take transportation as example. Upon arrival, we bought a Suica card, which is an alternative to the T-Money card used in Korea. It was pre-charged with ¥1500 of credit, which is approx. €15. We thought that it would be enough for the whole trip, because in Seoul charging 10,000KRW (= €6.60) is usually enough for up to two weeks. We were wrong — we had to recharge already the second day, and we haven't even used the card for the trip from the airport (¥1400, in Seoul approx. 3500-4000KRW). In total, I spent around €50 only for transport that weekend.

<strong>...taxis are <span style="color:#ff0000;">extremely</span> expensive. </strong>Talking about money, due unforeseen events (mixing up the trains and taking the last train in the opposite direction) we had to take a taxi from Kamata to Shibuya. This approx. 30 minute ride set us back with staggering €60 bill, which meant €20 per person. The most I have paid for a taxi in Seoul so far was €5 for a 40 minute ride at 5am from Hongdae. The funny thing is that in Tokyo, the increment per unit is 100, which is the same as in Seoul. Won is, however, worth 10 times less than Yen. Sad story...

The (only) funny part is that the taxis are ooooooooold. They really stand out between all the modern cars, and maybe their age is the reason for the price. Repairing a 20yr old Nissan must be quite financially demanding.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/01/you-know-you-are-in-tokyo-when/p1010017/" rel="attachment wp-att-275"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-275" title="An old taxi at Asaksabashi" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/p10100171.jpg?w=530" alt="An old taxi at Asaksabashi" width="530" height="353" /></a>

<strong>...girls are not wearing skirts. </strong>Technically, they are. But it does not seem so, since their skirts are merely belts. Well, I think I have even seen a wider belt. We were surprised despite being used to Korean girls, that dress up in heels and miniskirts even for taking out the trash. These nanoskirts, combined with knee-high socks and a lot of makeup makes Japanese girls look like dolls. Or <del>sluts </del> prostitutes, you choose. I guess it's just the culture, but it is quite funny when you see such girl walk with her mother (even young girls dress like that) and no one seems to care. No judging looks or remarks, slutty girls are simply part of the society. Not that we would complain about that, but it just feels weird.

<strong>...you go to a Maid Café. </strong>This is one of the things that you somehow expect to see in Japan. It is weird, it is crazy, it is to some extent perverted and regular Japanese would never go there. Maid Café is a café, where you are waited by girls dressed as French maids, with short skirts and in many cases with little tails and ears. Seriously. Even though it sounds like something I just made up, Akihabara is full of such café, which are targeted at Otaku, Japanese nerds (often grown man) that like anime and manga, and a French maid is one of their biggest fantasies. Don't ask me why. These guys go to these café, drink, eat, talk to their waitress, that really treat them like their master.

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="495" caption="Maids from a Maid Café (source: http://cryosites.com)"]<img title="Maid Café" src="http://www.cryosites.com/shared/img/m/maid_fnddh.jpeg" alt="Maid Café" width="495" height="329" />[/caption]

We got caught by a maid directly on the street, and since we wanted to go to a café anyway, we went with her. She was German, but assured us that she is the only non-Asian there, which made us feel even creepier than before. In the café, we got seated, received water and waited. Since this particular café did not have any cover charge (they normally do), the prices were higher than one would expect (coffee €6, beer €15). Their specialty was an omelette, on which they drew a picture with ketchup. Well, it was simply uncomfortable. Even though we though that it is hilarious, we felt creepy and perverted, watching these young-ish girls in their short dresses, talking to older Japanese guys. Before leaving we found out that during their tour, even Backstreet Boys came to this café to see maids and have a cup of coffee and an omelette. Well, I don't want it that way.

<strong>...people use three alphabets and you can't understand either of them.</strong> Kenji, Hiragana, Katakana. Each one has different purpose and looks different. In real world, they are, however mixed up together, so one word or phrase can contain all three of them. Thanks God for Hangul!

<strong>...the Eiffel tower is painted red and white.</strong>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter" title="Tokyo Tower" src="http://img.wikinut.com/img/27-uighgnfe-3-t7/jpeg/724x5000/Tokyo-tower.jpeg" alt="Tokyo Tower" width="530" /></p>
<strong>...everything is überclean.</strong> The Japanese pursuit for perfection is materialized in the cleanness of streets, cars, buildings and the environment in general. Since almost everybody has a job in Japan (unemployment rate &lt; 5%), some people simply clean the streets and everything. I don't know if it's simply because there are more cleaners than in other countries, people do not litter that much or the cleaners are perfectionists, but the streets in particular look like they have been cleaned with a vacuum cleaner. Even the traffic signs on the road look fresh and new. I really admire that, because what you can sometimes see here in Seoul is quite gross. Well, cultural difference is cultural difference:)

<strong>...you sometimes feel like you are a part of a big freak show.</strong> Even though we did not see the masses of cosplay people at Harajuku, following pictures speak for themselves.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/01/you-know-you-are-in-tokyo-when/p1010175/" rel="attachment wp-att-274"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-274" title="Cosplay @ Harajuku" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/p10101751.jpg?w=530" alt="Cosplay @ Harajuku" width="530" height="226" /></a>

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/01/you-know-you-are-in-tokyo-when/p1010177/" rel="attachment wp-att-273"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-273" title="Cosplay @ Harajuku" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/p10101771.jpg?w=530" alt="Cosplay @ Harajuku" width="530" height="336" /></a>More photos and maybe more stories might come in another blogpost. Otherwise you have to wait for my memoirs.]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>268</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-01 00:05:23</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-10-31 15:05:23</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>you-know-you-are-in-tokyo-when</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1320073525]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>22</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[elsa]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>elsa.snyder@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://concreteandsky.wordpress.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>84.83.109.200</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2011-11-01 00:52:17</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2011-10-31 15:52:17</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[It's Halloween every day in Japan.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>11512291</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1320076338]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1320076339.7348";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:7:"esnyder";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Between the South and the North</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 16:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=286</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[I did it. I went there. North Korea, officially the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, the evil twin of South Korea, the loser clenched in between the two Asian superpowers. Today, I, for the first time, stepped on the North Korean territory. The story behind it is not special, so I apologize to those of you who expected something from a lame action movie with explosions, car chases, spy gadgets and hot girls.

As we planned earlier, today we went on the "DMZ trip", i.e. trip to the demilitarized zone, which lies between North and South Korea. Despite it's name, DMZ is the most militarized border in the world, with permanent military presence on both sides, and it stretches across the whole Korean peninsula in a 4km wide corridor. For a regular mortal it is merely impossible to cross the border, because DPRK does not allow anyone from the South Korean side to cross the border. However, the DMZ, and the associated Joint Security Area (JSA) are partially opened for public through numerous agencies offering tour packages.

Our bus picked us up at the campus at 7:10am. Waking up so early was extremely painful, especially due to previous night at Indy Pub. My efforts to sleep in the bus were hampered by my slightly nauseous state, which fortunately got better 30 minutes into the trip. After picking up the rest of our tour group at Lotte Hotel, we set off for the DMZ, which is about 1hr drive from Seoul.

[caption id="attachment_288" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="Part of the group"]<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/p1010277/" rel="attachment wp-att-288"><img class="size-medium wp-image-288" title="Part of the group" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010277.jpg?w=530" alt="Part of the group" width="530" height="303" /></a>[/caption]

Our first stop was at the Freedom bridge, which was used as a place for trading prisoners of war after the Korean War in 1950s. As a first stop, it was not that interesting because it was simply a bridge. At least we got some breakfast, though:)
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/p1010280/" rel="attachment wp-att-287"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-287" title="Me at the Freedom Bridge with a plastic guard" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010280.jpg?w=390" alt="Me at the Freedom Bridge with a plastic guard" width="530" /></a></p>


[caption id="attachment_289" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="Our Breakfast — Meat on a stick"]<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/p1010279/" rel="attachment wp-att-289"><img class="size-medium wp-image-289" title="Our Breakfast" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010279.jpg?w=530" alt="Our Breakfast" width="530" height="297" /></a>[/caption]

The second stop was the <a title="Third Tunnel of Aggression" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Third_Tunnel_of_Aggression">3rd infiltration tunnel</a>, also called the Third Tunnel of Aggression. It is one of the tunnels that North Koreans were planning to use for their invasion to South Korea. So far, there have been 4 tunnels revealed, however, rumors say that there are many more unfinished. The fun fact about this tunnel is that in order to explain the existence of such tunnel during a cease fire time, North Koreans painted the walls of this tunnel black and claimed they were mining coal. The tunnel is still "open", i.e. it would theoretically be possible to go to the other side, however, there are 3 concrete barricades to avoid access from NK. The tunnel is 73m underground and access for tourists is realized by a very steep 300m shaft. The tunnel ceiling is quite low, which means you have to walk bent forward in order not to bang your helmet protected head into the ceiling. Even though there is nothing interesting to see at the end of the tunnel (no light, folks, sorry), I was curious what could possibly be at the other side of the barricades. I wonder if NK has some soldiers stationed there or if they had simply closed the tunnel at their side.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/p1010295/" rel="attachment wp-att-291"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-291" title="DMZ" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010295.jpg?w=530" alt="DMZ" width="530" height="353" /></a>

After the tunnel we climbed up the Dora Moutain, which offers a observatory from which you can see North Korea, including their fake propaganda village and the monstrous flagpole. Photographs are again not permitted, even though you can take pictures while standing behind a photo line approx. 10 m from the edge of the observation deck. The village comprises few "houses", that are demonstrating the advanced development of North Korea. While that might have worked in 1950s, telescopic lenses revealed that the houses are in fact not inhabited and without any household equipment or even window glass or doors.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/p1010319/" rel="attachment wp-att-293"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-293" title="People looking through binoculars" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010319.jpg?w=530" alt="People looking through binoculars" width="530" height="209" /></a><a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/p1010331/" rel="attachment wp-att-292"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-292" title="P1010331" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010331.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="134" /></a>The last stop of our DMZ tour was the Dorasan Train station, which is the last SK railroad station before North Korea. For a short period of time, the railroad was used to transport cargo to and from the Kaesong Industrial Region, however, because of <em>"Kim Jong-Il's frikkin mind"</em>, as our tour guide said, the border crossing was shut by NK in 2008. Nowadays, the station serves as a touristic attraction, even though there are few trains coming in every day. For 500KRW you can buy a "ticket" to Pyongyang and go wait on the platform. The train won't come though, so do not spend too much time waiting.
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/combo/" rel="attachment wp-att-299"><img class="size-medium wp-image-299 aligncenter" title="combo" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/combo.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="263" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">After lunch, which was a very disappointing bulgogi, we moved to a different bus and set off for the second part of our trip, the JSA. Before that, we were warned that the security measures and rules are much stricter than in the DMZ. First thing: No Koreans. For security reasons, Koreans are not allowed to participate in the JSA visit. Secondly, there is a dress code, which prohibits army-like clothes, shorts, flip-flops etc. Thirdly, no communication with North Koreans is allowed. This includes both verbal and non-verbal means, such as waving. Moreover, pointing is prohibited, as it may look like pointing a gun. Lastly, photography is even more restricted than in DMZ.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The JSA is a military facility that lies directly on the Military Demarcation Line. Half of it belongs to South Koreans, that operate it together with U.S. forces, and the second half is North Korean. It is the only place where the two sides directly face each other. It is understandable that the security precautions are so strict. Each bus got it's own armed "guard", that was taking care of our security during the visit. Our guy was a U.S. paratrooper named Muniz. After an ID check we went for a short briefing about the history of JSA, which was a little boring. The interesting part came afterwards. We embarked a military bus and went to visit the Freedom House.</p>


[caption id="attachment_300" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="The South Korean side of the neutral buildings — The big building in the background is North Korean Panmungak"]<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/p1010377/" rel="attachment wp-att-300"><img class="size-medium wp-image-300" title="The South Korean side of the neutral buildings" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010377.jpg?w=530" alt="The South Korean side of the neutral buildings" width="530" height="353" /></a>[/caption]

Some of you might have seen the JSA before. There are two main buildings — the Freedom House (SK) and Panmungak (NK). Between them is some sort of neutral zone, that is dissected by the Military Demarcation Line. In the center there are several blue buildings that serve as negotiation rooms for the representatives of the two sides. These houses are permanently guarded by elite soldiers and despite the terrible weather, the four SK soldiers were standing there in the rain, partially hidden behind the building, their shades on.

South Korea has pretty strong requirements on the JSA guards. Firstly, they have to be taller than 1,77m. Secondly, they have to have a black belt in either Taekwondo or Judo. The height serves as an intimidation tactics against North Koreans, that are generally smaller. Moreover, SK guards stand in a modified Taekwondo posture, that demonstrates power. They all wear black shades to increase the intimidation factor. Frankly, these guys look really scary, with their angry facial expressions and latent power, that is so apparent despite them standing absolutely still.

When we were waiting outside the negotiation building, there was no NK personnel on guard. However, one guy was standing in front of the Panmungak, observing us through binoculars. It was such a weird feeling, being watched by a North Korean guy, while taking pictures of him. I really wonder what was going through his head at the moment. It was quite a bizarre experience, and it seriously gave me chills — I was standing some 50 meters from North Korea, one of the currently most feared countries, chatting with friends and being all excited about seeing a "real North Korean". Weird.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/p1010382/" rel="attachment wp-att-301"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-301" title="North Korean dude" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010382.jpg?w=530" alt="North Korean dude" width="530" height="241" /></a>

The grand finale of the JSA visit was the negotiation building, which was at the time guarded by South Koreans, which allowed us to go to the North Korean side, effectively stepping on their territory.

[caption id="attachment_297" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="Right now I am standing in North Korea — South Korea is at the left side from the guard, North Korea on the right"]<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/p1010393/" rel="attachment wp-att-297"><img class="size-medium wp-image-297" title="Me in North Korea" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010393.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="430" /></a>[/caption]

[caption id="attachment_298" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="The Demarcation Line as seen from the neutral house"]<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/05/between-the-south-and-the-north/p1010388/" rel="attachment wp-att-298"><img class="size-medium wp-image-298" title="The Demarcation Line" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010388.jpg?w=530" alt="The Demarcation Line" width="530" height="293" /></a>[/caption]

After that we returned to our bus and went home. I managed to sleep all the way to Seoul, partially reducing my sleeping debt.

So, DMZ+JSA, thumbs up or down? I have mixed feelings about that. The first part (DMZ) was not really exciting. Yes, we got to see a bridge and a tunnel, but that is not really connected to the current reality, which devaluates the experience for me. Especially because all the places are "tricked out" for turists, so it is not even something pure and raw. On the other hand, the JSA was quite amazing. We all felt that there is a latent threat in the air, that probably won't be realized, but you never know. Two armed soldiers in each bus and a jeep with few more in the front showed that everybody takes the situation seriously. After all, I am happy that I went on this trip. It was expensive, I have to admit that, but it was also quite a unique experience. And honestly, who had been to North Korea, huh?]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>286</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-05 01:02:37</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-04 16:02:37</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>between-the-south-and-the-north</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1320422560]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Best College Day™</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/08/the-best-college-day/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 16:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=308</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<em>Writing a blog is sometimes quite hard. Yesterday, this post had almost 1100 words. Then I realized it is boring and too "iterative" (I did this and then that and after that something else), and I deleted it, because I promised to myself that I won't write in this "diary" style. You are not interested in my daily life, right...so instead of writing a lot of stuff about The Best College Day™, I will try to keep it short so you have enough time to do your own things. So watch a movie afterwards. Or walk your dog. Or something...</em>

There are few things that you need to have the best day. <strong>The weather</strong> has to be nice. There has to be some <strong>activity that you like</strong>. There have to be your <strong>friends</strong>. There has to be some good <strong>food</strong>. There have to be <strong>drinks</strong>. There has to be<strong> the right mood</strong>. Combine all that, and you have the best recipe for an awesome day. Just do not overcook it, please.

Firstly, the weather. On Thursday, November 3rd, the weather was amazing. The sun was shining, the sky was blue, the birds were singing. I was walking around just in a t-shirt, because it was so warm. So weather — <span style="color:#99cc00;">check!</span>

Favorite activities. Hmm, that might be more difficult. I like a lot of things — bikes, music, bass, golf, running, you name it. But I don't have my bass or my bike here, there are no good concerts around and running on a treadmill is not that exciting either. So what is left? Yep, golf. As a part of the KAIST Autumn Festival, there was a screen golf competition, in which I participated. I sucked, honestly, partly because my golf skills were too big to bring them to Holland and then to Seoul, but I had an awesome time, because I could play a round just for fun — no ambitions, no scorecards, no pressure. <span style="color:#99cc00;">Check!</span>

Friends. This one is easy. I really like our exchange group here, as well as other full time students. And since no student ever refuses free things, everybody was participating. <span style="color:#99cc00;">Check!</span>

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="Kate, André, Marc, me (doing Korean photo pose) and Rik (photo by Sultan)"]<img class=" " title="The group" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/s720x720/380819_10150364048189792_503714791_7694381_1133824998_n.jpg" alt="" width="530" />[/caption]

And that brings me to the food and drinks issue. For the festival, KAIST provided food and drinks for everybody. Chicken wings, kimbap, pancakes, sweets, sours, everything was there. And tap beer as well. And, of course, everything for free. If you consider that the "food court" was located outside, in the middle of the campus, under the sun and the blue sky...so <span style="color:#99cc00;">check</span> as well!

And now to the difficult part, the mood. You can't influence that. But the state of the world can. It's hard to have a bad mood when you are having a good time. <span style="color:#99cc00;">Check!</span>

So, to sum it up. Last Thursday was perfect. I think I really had The Best College Day™ so far. Apart from all the things mentioned above, I have also participated in a beer drinking competition, saw a K-POP performance, had a BigMac menu delivered to the campus, went dancing, sang Backstreet Boys and ended up with orange ribbons tied to my glasses. And I won a little mechanical snail in a raffle. Seriously, that sounds like fun, right...

And <strong><span style="color:#99cc00;">check</span></strong>!]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>308</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-08 01:57:41</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-07 16:57:41</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-best-college-day</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1320685062]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[the-best-college-day-ever]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Fieeeeeeld triiiiiip!</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/12/fieeeeeeld-triiiiiip/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=323</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[After two months of Korean Business and Culture lectures we finally got to do our first field trip. The destination was a Korean corporation (not as big as a <em>chaebol</em>) Kolmar, that specialized on cosmetics and pharma products. We have visited their Sinjeong factory, which comprises a pharma factory, a pharma R&amp;D lab and a skin care factory.

To educate you a little, let me give you a quick review of the history of the company. Compared to big Korean corporations, Kolmar is quite young — it was founded only 21 years ago in 1990. Its parent company was Kolmar Americas Inc., that manages the global network of Kolmar Global. The Korean branch was established as a joint-venture with Kolmar Japan.

At first, Kolmar Korea focused mainly on cosmetics. One of their strategy was "perfection", which lead to CGMP (Cosmetic Good Manufacturing Practice) certification in 1994. Until 2000, the company continued growing and received several awards and prizes for their results and development. In 2001 they were the first ones to receive the ISO9001 certification (Quality Management certification) in Korea. Year 2002 marked the beginning of the pharmaceutical business, as well as KGMP certification of all facilities. They were also listed at the KRX (Korea Exchange) in the same year. In the following years, they have enlarged the portfolio of manufactured products and strengthened their R&amp;D capabilities by extending the R&amp;D labs and centers. In 2007, a Chinese spin-off, Kolmar Beijing, was established to simplify access to the Chinese market. Between 2000 and 2010, Kolmar was awarded several other certifications, such as Ecocert, Lohas or ISO 14001, and in 2011, they received as the first Korean company the ISO 22716 certification for good manufacturing practices in cosmetics.

Currently, the company focuses on subsidiary manufacturing and R&amp;D for companies such as L'Oreal, Shiseido, P&amp;G, Unilever, Dior or Johnson-Johnson. They also supply local Korean manufacturers (Nature Republic, Beyond, Tonymoly or The FaceShop). The CEO is 윤동한 (Yoon, Dung-Han), and they have approx. 1000 employees.

The field trip begun in the morning, when we gathered at the main gate of our campus. Since not all exchange students participated in the trip, the bus was half empty, so almost everybody got the double seat for their own. I assume that the ride was nice, but I can't tell you any details, because I immediately fell asleep after departing from KAIST and woke up few minutes before arriving to the factory. As mentioned above, we visited the Sinjeong factory, which is about 1:40h from Seoul.

Upon arrival, we had to take of our shoes and take on some slippers instead, however, since my foot is bigger than average Korean (I have 290, which is usually the biggest size they have in shops), it was not very comfortable.  What was comfortable, however, was the provided "french coffee" in the presentation room, where we got a formal welcoming speech and a short introduction about the company.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/12/fieeeeeeld-triiiiiip/p1010418/" rel="attachment wp-att-324"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-324" title="Fancy lab tools" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010418.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="263" /></a>

The first stop on our factory tour was the pharma R&amp;D lab. I was really surprised, that there were no scurity measures at all. We could take any photos and our movement was virtually unrestricted. We were walking through the labs, where various liquids were bubbling or swirling, and different screens were showing different graphs or curves. Fancy stuff indeed! I even got a souvenir — a capsule from a capsule maker. I am not sure what's inside, but it's cool. I will give it to someone as a Christmas present, I guess...just kidding, it's all mine!

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/12/fieeeeeeld-triiiiiip/p1010404/" rel="attachment wp-att-325"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-325" title="Capsule making thingie" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010404.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="353" /></a>

The second part was a visit to the skin care factory. For that, we had to take on shoe covers, lab coats and hairnets. It is amazing how a group of MBA students can turn into a bunch of kids when they are given a hair net and shoe covers that you can slide on.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/12/fieeeeeeld-triiiiiip/p1010430/" rel="attachment wp-att-326"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-326" title="A group of weirdos in weird clothes" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010430.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="261" /></a>

Our excitement levels got even higher when they told us we have to go through an air shower. 8 people at a time went into a sealed chamber, where a set of air jets got rid of particles that could influence the manufacturing process. Even though we could observe the manufacturing process only through a window, we saw the complete filling and packaging process, as well as the storage are for the creams and stuff before packaging. <a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/12/fieeeeeeld-triiiiiip/p1010431/" rel="attachment wp-att-327"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-327" title="Packaging and quality control" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010431.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="315" /></a>

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/12/fieeeeeeld-triiiiiip/p1010440/" rel="attachment wp-att-329"><img class="aligncenter" title="Barrels full of magic" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010440.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="198" /></a>

It is weird to see the big blue barrels full of creams, that are waiting to be packaged into small tubes. I bet many girls would be happy to have access to such barrel. After some more time of sliding through to corridor, we got out through the air shower chamber (no shower this time, though), and went for lunch. The bulgogi was decent, as was the soup and other things.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/12/fieeeeeeld-triiiiiip/p1010446/" rel="attachment wp-att-330"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-330" title="Bulgogi!" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010446.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="311" /></a>After lunch we had the last part of our field trip — presentation of Kolmar's business model in Korea. A big part of it was already presented in the "history" part, so I will just quickly summarize my impressions. Kolmar largely focuses on the quality of their manufacturing process. Multiple certifications clearly show their determination to comply with all different quality requirements given by both Korean (KFDI) and international agencies, and provide leverage for cooperation with foreign subjects. Currently, they are the only ODM (Original Design Manufacturer) in Korea, which gives means a great potential for growth on both local and foreign market. By not focusing solely on manufacturing, but also in R&amp;D (in 2009 their R&amp;D-to-sales ratio of 6% was about 3% higher than their competitors') they also profile themselves as an innovative company with active development, which as well increases their leverage for their customers.

In future, it is possible that Kolmar will launch their own brand of cosmetics (not that probable for pharma), in which they would utilize all the experience gained during partnership with some of the biggest cosmetics companies in the world, as well as in Korea. In my opinion, it would make more sense to target the local market, because I feel like Koreans are still very much inclined toward local products than imported ones.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/12/fieeeeeeld-triiiiiip/p1010444/" rel="attachment wp-att-328"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-328" title="Colorful palettes" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010444.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="154" /></a>

This is the end of one of the most boring posts on my blog so far. I am sorry if I bored you to death, but there is a reason for this post — I want to use it as a foundation for my report for the KBC class, so I figured that it would be easier to first summarize the trip in more informal manner, and then build the report based on the blogpost than vice versa. So stay tuned, there will be more funny posts soon!]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>323</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-12 22:00:47</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-12 13:00:47</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>fieeeeeeld-triiiiiip</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1321102847]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Culinary Adventures II.</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/15/culinary-adventures-ii/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 13:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=337</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>Me: "So, how is the food in Korea?"
Roman: "Well, do you like spicy food?"
Me: "Yeah, kind of."
Roman: "They you'll like it..."</blockquote>
This was my conversation with my friend Roman few days before coming to Korea. After more than two months here, my response to his question would probably be different. It's not that I don't like spicy food anymore, I just don't like the Korean kind of spicy. And who or what is to blame? The cafeteria! As I realize it now, the only spicy food that I did not like was from the KAIST cafeteria (and the curry place, but that was probably caused by my hangover). It does not matter if it was the "weird meat in a brown sauce" (for my Czech readers, it is like some kind of UHO) or the "kimchi rice", it was just too spicy and tasteless. I know that you might say "you have to get used to it" or "you are a sissy" or even "OMG WTF, you are lame and you suck, ROFL", but I just can't help it. I like food that tastes good already the first time, not after 3 months of "getting used to", especially because there are so many other opportunities to eat good food.

<em>(The fun part of this post ends here...but there is still some interesting info down there, so just carry on reading...)</em>

Last time I promised to walk you through some of the places we go to. The problem is, that I find such descriptive writing quite boring. So I will try to keep it as short as possible...I hope you don't mind...
<h1>Fast foods</h1>
What would be do without good old fastfood chains, right. In the immediate vicinity to our campus, there are several branches of both Korean and foreign fast food chains.

The most famous one is definitely <strong>Burger King</strong>. The only special thing about Korean BK's is the Bulgogi Burger, a local specialty with beef and a special bulgogi sauce. Honestly, I prefer the classical Whopper and based on my observations, so do Koreans. As opposed to other FF chains, most BK's in Korea are open 24/7.

Another burger place is a Korean chain called <strong>Young-Cheol Burger</strong>. They do not serve classical burgers, but most of their so called burgers are more like Subway subs with ham and vegetables. I really appreciate that every sub is freshly made, so you are sure it has not been sitting on the shelf for already 20 minutes.

Moving on...<strong>Isaac Toast</strong>. A small but nice place, where they sell toasts. Since their menu is only in Korean and I haven't bothered with translation, I do not know what toasts they have, except for a M.V.P. toast, which has a beef patty, egg, raddish, cheese and three sauces. The important thing is that it's good, relatively cheap and it certainly fills you up.

And now to the sweet stuff. Right next to our regular place there is <strong>Dunkin' Donuts</strong>, where we usually buy our dessert after eating at the regular place. Across the street from it there is <strong>Baskin Robbins</strong> (ice cream), and a little further up the street there is <strong>Starbucks</strong>, surrounded by dozen other coffeeshop, that are bigger, cheaper and not-at-all ripping off the image of SBs with a round logo and a bold, sans-serif font.
<h1>Tonkatsu!</h1>
Tonkatsu with cheese, rice and salad. A little bowl of miso soup on the side. Yum! The Japanese fried pork cutlet (tonkatsu) is suprisingly very popular in Korea, any you can find it in almost any restaurant that does not specialize on some specific cuisine. There are two places that we sometimes go to for tonkatsu — one serves the tonkatsu as described above, as well as some udong noodles, sushi and other Japanese things, while the other one is more inclined towards Italian cuisine, and serves the cutlet with mozzarella and bolognese saucejifydshfnfbchvgwhfkc.

<em>(And this is the place where I stopped having fun writing this and my head fell on my keyboard...)</em>

Sometimes I feel the obligation to write informative stuff to educate people and tell them something about Korean culture. It also helps me to better sort out my thoughts and experiences. As you might have noticed, I do like to write stuff. But it has to be something at least remotely interesting for me and for you. And frankly, <strong>I don't think anyone is interested in this phonebook of places to eat anymore.</strong>

<strong>You know, food is quite a difficult thing to write about. It is awesome to eat, in most cases nice to look at and smell, for me also fun to cook, but it is quite boring to write about, especially when I need to remember all the places and food and look it up on Wikipedia to describe it properly. So if you don't mind, I will try to summarize my ad interim Culinary Adventures in one short paragraph.</strong>

Korean cuisine is awesome. Bulgogi, Kimbap, Mandu, Galbi, Kimchi, Ramen, Bibimbap, Udong, yellow raddish, white raddish, chopsticks, meat on the stick, everything. Apart from the cafeteria and a pork intestine place, everything has been at least acceptable, but in most cases good or delicious. If you ever come to Korea, go for it and try the local meals. You don't have to worry, even though they do eat dogs and live octopus, it's not really common. So go ahead, take your flat metal chopsticks and enjoy your meal. And remember, rice is eaten with a spoon and you should never stick your chopsticks into the ricebowl.

<em>N.B.: Sorry for this messy post...I really wanted to write about the food here, but I guess I just took it from the wrong side. I'll try to sum everything up at the end, so if you now think I am merely crazy, don't judge me and wait for December. If you don't change your opinion by then, then I probably really am crazy.</em>]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>337</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-15 22:57:07</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-15 13:57:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>culinary-adventures-ii</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1321365429]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Time goes by...</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/18/time-goes-by/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 11:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=346</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[Seriously, is it Friday again? That's serious mess. Time flies so fast, and even though one proverb says that <em>"Time flies when you have fun"</em>, I really did not expect it fly that fast.

Not all stuff is that cool, though. Yesterday some mofo <em>stole</em> some money from my wallet in the gym. I forgot it in my pants in an unlocked locker and someone just seized the given opportunity. I lost approx. 150,000 KRW, which is something like €96. Yeah, bummer. Since the locker is in the shower room, there is no CCTV and I really do not remember all the people that went to the gym while I was working out. Well, it's gone now, so there is nothing I can do, except for crying and punching someone in the face. Life does sometimes suck...

Today I've decided to do nothing and hopefully catch up on the slack I have with my blog. There are at least two posts that I have on my mind, but did not get to the writing part. I guess I need some (female) assistant to do that for me.

To give you brief heads up — on Tuesday we went on another field trip, about which I will write later, because it was completely awesome. After that I finally got to see the War Memorial, which almost concludes the list of touristic places in Seoul that I wanted to visit. Yeah, check!

On Wednesday me and Marc paid another visit to "our" tailor in Itaewon, where we had the first fitting of our suits. Yep, I am having a suit done here. I was a little nervous about the color, because I was not sure how it would look on the completed suit. Well, the fitting exceeded my expectations. Despite not being completed, the suit fit me so well. And the color was perfect, too. Damn, I am going to look so hot in that suit! Ladies will go crazy...

Yesterday's night was in the name of <del>love</del> clubbing again. Despite all the heroic statements, we ended up being just 4 — Kate, Morgan, Marc and me. At around 11:20pm, after zero pre-gaming, we took a taxi to Hongdae to Club Naked, where the "School Uniform Party Vol. II" was supposed to take place. Frankly, I have not seen a single school uniform that night. What I have seen, though, was a lot of white faces. The club was packed with foreigners, which seriously sucked. A big part of the people in the club were "stylish douchebags" from prestigious French business schools, that behaved like the club was theirs. Damn, I really got unused to the European testosteron fueled club behavior.

After about an hour in the club, we "took" André and went to Cocoon, which was much better, since there were almost no foreginers and we could dance on the stage and be cool. Yea, this is how we rolled.

Tomorrow, we are planning to go see the Lantern Festival in the city center, which is supposed to be pretty, so I'll try to snap some pictures for your viewing pleasure.]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>346</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-18 20:20:33</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-18 11:20:33</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>time-goes-by</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1321615233]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Experience the future (and the past)</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/19/experience-the-future-and-the-past/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 05:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=349</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[Tuesday was a special day. I got to experience both the future and the past. And no, Dr. Emmet Brown was not involved, and neither was a DeLorean or Marty McFly. But damn, that would be cool if they were. Anyway, on Tuesday, we went to the SK T.um, which is a showroom of SK Telecom, the biggest mobile operator in Korea.

<img class="alignright" title="T.um" src="http://itviewpoint.com/files/attach/images/129/072/088/IMG_4849.jpg" alt="" width="250" />

The<em> "um"</em> stands for <em>"Ubiquitous Museum"</em>, which just seems like a fancy name, because it does not really make sense. However, the whole place is completely awesome, especially for a geek and techie like me.

Firstly, at the beginning of the tour, you receive a Samsung Galaxy S II, which is in T.um terminology called the <em>T.key</em>. The phone is equipped with a special <em>T.um</em> app and unfortunately it is otherwise locked up (you can't access the underlying Android). After filling in your name, age group, e-mail and telephone, and taking a picture of yourself, you go to a Pond, where your <em>T.me</em> (virtual avatar) drops from the ceiling in a form of a water drop <em>(fancy stuff!)</em>. The <em>T.me</em> then follows you during the whole tour. These things are possible thanks to the integrated ZigBee based short-range communication chip in the phone, which allows it to interact with the objects in the exposition and deliver location based data.

The first part of the tour is called <strong>"Play Dream"</strong>. It is basically a presentation of <em>"ubiquitous life service"</em>, i.e. a service that will be fully integrated into our life.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/19/experience-the-future-and-the-past/tum/" rel="attachment wp-att-354"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-354" title="T.um" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/tum.png?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="432" /></a>

The first part is dedicated to <em>Communication and Entertainment</em>, and it is called the <em>U.home</em>. I assume that it stands for "Ubiquitous Home", which is, well, something...Nah, that <em>"U"</em> shit does not make sense. The room is equipped with three beamers that form a huge screen. The screen is controlled by gestures, however, since they use an IR strip and a cam, the recognition is a little slow. Such thing would be much better with a Kinect-like technology. That would make it truly Minority Report-like. Just without the murders and Tom Cruise.

The room also includes a "multimedia table", which is something like the Surface table from Microsoft. It is a big screen, that is NFC enabled, so putting the T.key device/mobile phone on the table enables interaction between the table and the phone. That way you can watch movies or pictures from the phone on the table or the big screen without any cables or docks. We made our tour guide play a Girls Generation music video on the huge screen, which made all the guys much happier...What I really liked was direct transfer of files between two phones laying on the table. The transfer was however done via 3G/WiFi, as ZigBee is not built for high speed transfer between devices.

The second room was focused on <em>Gaming (U.entertainment)</em>. That was a little lame, because using the phone's accelerometer for controlling a game via 3G/WiFi/ZigBee is quite sluggish. We were doing some racing and I finished second, so I am not complaining, but still, it would need improvement for real world deployment. Funny thing was when the guide was reading who is on which position and said "On the second position is........Honza........is that your real name?". Umm, no, madam, I just made it up...

Next part was <em>"U.driving"</em>, which included a real car mounted on a hydraulic platform. The car was called Spira, which is a new Korean-made sportscar. Morgan and Lauriane were the two "volunteers", so they had to go through a simulated ride. The mobile phone acted as a central controller, displaying information about the car (telemetry), serving as a GPS satnav, allowing to pay for the fuel (ehm, electricity) and do other funny things. Frankly, this part was not that impressive, because this is something that will be quite hard to achive in larger scale, thanks to the fragmentation of in-car systems, but it is a nice concept, that could make driving easier.

While they were still driving, we moved to the next section focused on content creation (<em>U.media</em>). In this part our photos from the phone were used to create a 3D advertisement. Since it was just a 2D picture, the photos were simply used as a texture, so you can imagine how it looked. Moreover, the 3D effect was not that good, so I would say this was the weakest part of the exhibition.

<em>U.fashion</em>. Girl's heaven, guy's hell. Through a 3D scanner, Karin's body was scanned, analyzed (height and other things) and digitalized. That allowed her to virtually try on various clothes and outfits. I think this might be quite useful, because it saves time and effort. I don't understand why the virtual avatar was standing in a middle of an intersection, though. As usual, the "app" allowed you to buy the clothes right after trying them on, without having to leave your home. It would be nice if a 3D printer could print them for you instead:)

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="The 3D full body scanner"]<img class=" " title="The body scanner" src="http://sktstory.com/wp-content/uploads/1/499b64f6ede60AZ.jpg" alt="" width="530" />[/caption]

Last part of the "Play Dream" concept was U.<em>shopping</em>. Based on our profile, the system recommended us some goods, which we could directly buy. Every product was associated with some short "game", which allowed you to "try before you buy". This concept does not seem that impressive, considering the recommendation algorithms used by e-shop or the <a href="http://www.designboom.com/weblog/cat/16/view/15557/tesco-virtual-supermarket-in-a-subway-station.html" target="_blank">"virtual" shopping mall</a> in the Seoul subway.

Since we were in quite a hurry, we only ran through the second part of the exposition called <strong>"Play Real"</strong>. While "the dream" showcased what will be available in the future, "the real" showcased what is already available. There was an augmented reality app for factory controlling, which is supposedly already used, a dock for the mobile that allowed instant switch from the phone to a big TV (erm, HDMI all the way...) and a CSR thing, which I did not understand, because I really have no idea what does CSR have in common with visually impaired people.

And that was the end of the tour. We did not get the chance to try out all the gadgets and thingies in the Play Real section, so we just returned our T.keys and went home.

Well, only some of us went home...André, Marc and I went for a lunch to Lotteria (Giant Double Burger set FTW!) and then we took a cab to the War Memorial in Yonsan. The WM was the last thing that I really wanted to see among the touristic places in Seoul. And it was also one of the coolest. The memorial, as its name hints, is a museum of all the wars and occupations the Korean peninsula has experienced so far.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/19/experience-the-future-and-the-past/p1010471/" rel="attachment wp-att-355"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-355" title="The War Memorial Museum" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010471.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="253" /></a>

The exposition is quite cool, actually. Of course, it is nationalistic and to some extent over-the-top, but that is understandable. This country has been through a lot of wars (almost as much as the Czech Republic), and the scars are still visible. The most notable one is, of course, the DMZ and the separation of the two Koreas. The museum is divided into several rooms, with each one representing different part of Korean military history (Memorial Hall, War History, Korean War, Expeditionary Forces Room, ROK Armed Forces Room, and Large Equipment Room). Each of these rooms displays all the important things, such as uniforms, weapons, paintings of battles etc. Obviously, the biggest part is dedicated to the Korean war, with 3D battle scenes, models, videos etc. There is even a "Combat Experience Simulator", which is a simulation of the combat using lights, sounds, smell etc. To absorb all the information in the memorial one would have to spend the whole day there, which we could not since André had a meeting later that afternoon.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/19/experience-the-future-and-the-past/p1010511/" rel="attachment wp-att-356"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-356" title="P1010511" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010511.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="268" /></a>

The memorial also has an outside exhibition space, with different pieces of military vehicles and planes. There are both UN/S. Korean and Chinese/USSR/N. Korean machines ranging from AA guns and Howitzers over tanks, armoured vehicles and fighter jets to big bombers, such as B-52. There is also a replica of a guard ship that got involved in a naval battle against North Korea, however, I can't remember the details. We were really excited about it — such place is definitely every guy's dream...:)

[caption id="attachment_358" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="A B-52...that thing is HUGE!"]<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/19/experience-the-future-and-the-past/p1010478/" rel="attachment wp-att-358"><img class="size-medium wp-image-358" title="A B-52...that thing is HUGE!" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010478.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="207" /></a>[/caption]

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="Marc and André standing next to the landing gear of a B-52"]<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/19/experience-the-future-and-the-past/p1010476/" rel="attachment wp-att-359"><img title="B-52 landing gear" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010476.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="302" /></a>[/caption]

[caption id="attachment_357" align="aligncenter" width="530" caption="&quot;Oh Captain, my Captain...&quot; — André is on a boat!"]<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/19/experience-the-future-and-the-past/p1010510/" rel="attachment wp-att-357"><img class="size-medium wp-image-357" title="Oh Captain, my Captain." src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1010510.jpg?w=530" alt="Oh Captain, my Captain..." width="530" height="283" /></a>[/caption] ]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>349</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-19 14:17:58</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-19 05:17:58</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>experience-the-future-and-the-past</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1321679878]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Shine Your Light</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/23/shine-your-light/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 15:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=369</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[Writing this post finally made me look up the song I have had in my head since Saturday. I could remember just few lines from it and I could not remember the rest or who it sings. Now I now, it was Roxette — Love Is All (Shine Your Light). And why I had this song in my head? Because of the light!<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/23/shine-your-light/img_2060/" rel="attachment wp-att-377"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-377" title="" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/img_2060.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="134" /></a>

Until last Sunday, Seoul had hosted the traditional Lantern Festival on the Cheonggyecheon Stream in the City Hall area downtown Seoul. To let some more culture into our lifes, we have decided to go there. At first, it was Kate, Marc, André, Rik and me. Since Marc was meeting some friend earlier, it was just Kate, André, Rik and me. Well, and because Kate had some other things to do, it was just...I think you know now.

Upon arriving to City Hall, we have discovered three things. Firstly, there was a huge "Occupy Seoul" demonstration in front of the City Hall. For unknown reasons, these people were protesting against the FTA with the US, which is weird, because I thought that it was generally accepted very well. The second thing was the presence of riot police in the whole neighborhood — police buses, anti-riot vehicles and policemen in full body armor with shields, everything looked like there was going to be a huge fight. The third thing was my SD card, or rather its absence. As soon as I took out my camera, I realized that the card is still in my laptop, which gave me space for only two or three pictures in the internal memory. Fortunately André was there to save the day, so all the photos in this post are from him. Merci beaucoup!

Before coming to the festival we made a short detour to Lotteria for a Giant Double Burger set (912 Kcal of pure awesomeness) and then straight to the lanterns! Well, not that straight. Since it was the penultimate night, there was quite a queue that was twisting and turning between the barriers. Even though we managed to jump part of the queue by simply walking next to all the people (smart guys), eventually we reached the point where we had to re-join the queue and wait. And wait. And wait. In total, we waited for approx. 20 minutes, which was quite uncomfortable, since it was around 0°C.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/23/shine-your-light/img_2063/" rel="attachment wp-att-371"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-371" title="Entrance gate" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/img_2063.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="274" /></a>

The lanterns are located directly in the middle of the Cheonggyecheon stream, which is a small artificial creek with pathways on both sides. You were supposed to walk on the right side and return on the left one, which, surprisingly, worked out quite well. The "statues" were lighted using electric bulbs, as fire would be too unstable/dangerous/stupid. It was quite interesting to see all the electric cables in the water, but I guess they just had good insulation. Or insurance.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/23/shine-your-light/img_2081/" rel="attachment wp-att-373"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-373" title="IMG_2081" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/img_2081.jpg?w=397" alt="" width="397" height="530" /></a>

The whole exhibition was also some kind of contest, however, I am not sure about the rules or where the participants came from. The themes of the lanters ranged from traditional Korean figures, over some Japanese figures, statues depicting child games, animals or abstract shapes to superheroes. Simply everything.

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/23/shine-your-light/img_2089/" rel="attachment wp-att-372"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-372" title="IMG_2089" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/img_2089.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="244" /></a>

Approximately in the middle of the exhibition, there was a stand where you could buy your own lantern (real one with a candle) and put it in the stream. This surely looked romantic, unfortunately, these lanterns were stopped after few meters by a metal barrier, where they just kept piling up and setting themselves on fire. Not so romantic anymore.
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/23/shine-your-light/img_2098/" rel="attachment wp-att-375"><img class=" wp-image-375 aligncenter" title="Batman" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/img_2098.jpg?w=530" alt="Batman lantern" width="530" height="508" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/23/shine-your-light/img_2077/" rel="attachment wp-att-374"><img class=" wp-image-374 aligncenter" title="The Human Centipede" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/img_2077.jpg?w=530" alt="The Human Centipede" width="530" height="396" /></a></p>
The festival was really nice. Seeing all those colorful lanters glow in the dark was amazing, especially in the combination with the creek. Since the creek is below ground level, I felt nicely isolated from the outer world, as well as the cold weather. The only bad thing about it was that we were not able to get any donuts afterwards. C'mon, people, 11pm is not too late for a donut, duh!

<a href="http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/11/23/shine-your-light/img_2107/" rel="attachment wp-att-376"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-376" title="IMG_2107" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/img_2107.jpg?w=530" alt="" width="530" height="343" /></a>

Btw. on our way back to City Hall, there was no demonstration or riot police. I don't know if they beat the crap out of them or if they just went away, but it was a little strange, because the place really looked like nothing has ever happened there.]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>369</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-23 00:03:05</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-22 15:03:05</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>shine-your-light</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1321974187]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[377]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
