<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress.com" created="2011-11-12 14:02"-->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.1/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.1/"
>

<channel>
	<title>S(e)oul eXchange</title>
	<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>One blue-eyed boy in a sea of rice, kimchi, K-POP and mobile phones.</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 14:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.1</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://wordpress.com/</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>9130441</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>swaycz</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>honza@egoistic.biz</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[honza]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='soulexchange.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>S(e)oul eXchange</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	
	<item>
		<title>안녕하세요</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/08/%ec%95%88%eb%85%95%ed%95%98%ec%84%b8%ec%9a%94/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 14:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=11</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Writing a diary does not work for me. The longest time I was able to regularly update a diary was about 2 weeks. The problem is not lack of interesting stuff to write down. The problem is either too much stuff to write down or good ol' laziness. Especially the latter, which also causes that there is still no post about my Kenyan adventure, even though those 15 days were überawesome. Anyway, here I will try to write down some interesting points about my 4 months in Seoul, South Korea. Btw. I have no idea what "soul exchange" could possibly mean, I just liked the joke in it. And if you don't consider it funny...
<h3>28.8.</h3>
<ul>
	<li>Emirates cabin crew's portfolio of languages is very impressive</li>
	<li>The last Pirates of Carribean are boring. On the other hand, The Best Movie Ever Sold is hilarious.</li>
	<li>Dubai Airport is boring. Everything is supersized and full of bling. And there is not enough space to sit down. Seriously, people, 30 seats at the gate are not enough for a flight that is operated by 500+ Airbus A380. However, the airport is quite cheap. A McD menu is 24 of their funnymoney (United Arab Emirates Dirham, to be precise), which is around 4,60 Euros. And you don't have to pay extra for ketchup.</li>
	<li>Airbus A380 is H-U-G-E! It's like a A320 after three years on steroids. And the ICE on-board entertainment system is supercool. They did not have Fight Club or Bring Me The Horizon on it, though.</li>
	<li>Incheon airport has a cool train between the terminal and main building.</li>
	<li>It was supercool that my mentor picked me up at the airport. I was just a little disappointed that he did not have a big sign with my name:)</li>
	<li>Seoul is less dense than I expected. It perfectly fulfills the idea of an Asian supercity, though.</li>
	<li>Kia, Hyundai, Kia, Daewoo, Hyundai, Samsung (!), Kia, Ssangyong, Chinese Mercedes rip-off, that's how the streets look like. Ah, there is one BMW, nice. The import tax on non-Korean cars is so high that people can't afford them (I heard).</li>
	<li>I think I might be a little too old for a shared room in a dorm, where toilets and showers are shared with another 10 people. Makes me miss my spacebox...</li>
	<li>Korean TV shows are just insane!</li>
</ul>
<h3>29.8.</h3>
<ul>
	<li>Cold noodles for lunch. Seriously?</li>
	<li>KIMCHIIIII!</li>
</ul>
<h3>30.8.</h3>
<div>
<ul>
	<li>Rice + soup + Kimchi = Korean breakfast. No, thanks, once was more than enough.</li>
	<li>No internet access for us yet. Sad sad situation. Thanks god for Kim's network.</li>
	<li>Orientation!</li>
	<li>Mobile phones everywhere. IM-ing or watching TV, everybody plays with his phone.</li>
	<li>Once you get used to their kind of beauty, Korean girls are pretty.</li>
	<li>Immigration office is a bureaucratic mess. Thanks god we had an appointment set by the uni.</li>
	<li>A/C everywhere. It's quite uncomfortable to change environments so often, because outside it's hot and humid and inside it's freezing.</li>
	<li>Lunch with the dean. Free food!</li>
	<li>Mentor-mentee meeting. My mentor absent, though. Took that opportunity to join the group with the pretties mentor around.</li>
</ul>
<h3>31.8.</h3>
<ul>
	<li>This uni has some cool spots at the campus.</li>
	<li>My registration for the school portal does not work.</li>
	<li>Korean culture demonstration. Trying on clothes and eating some sweets.</li>
	<li>Internet in the dorm. Amazing!</li>
	<li>Bud Bar in the evening. A 3L pitcher of Cass for 11,000 KRW (less than 6E). First late night return to the dorm. Welcome, exchange.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>1.9.</h3>
<div>
<ul>
	<li>School starts. Well, no classes for me yet, but still...</li>
	<li>The portal registration still does not work for me.</li>
	<li>Party night in Hongdae. Dinner (very spicy), beers and then Cocoon club. Sweet dance moves, me being the second tallest guy around, our group dominating the stage (hell yeah!), coming back at 6AM.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>2.9.</h3>
<div>
<ul>
	<li>Hangover.</li>
	<li>Still no portal access.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>3.9.</h3>
<div>
<ul>
	<li>Being touristic — visiting the National Museum of Korea and taking zillions of photos.</li>
</ul>
<h3>4.9.</h3>
<div>
<ul>
	<li>Lazy sunday</li>
	<li>First time to the KAIST gym. It has several advantages - it is 24/7, it is close and it is for free. /me likes it.</li>
	<li>First week in Seoul is done. And it was awesome. Another 15 to go!</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>11</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-08 14:45:41</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-08 14:45:41</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>%ec%95%88%eb%85%95%ed%95%98%ec%84%b8%ec%9a%94</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1315493142]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Explanation</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/09/explanation/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 04:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=17</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Just to make sure that everybody knows whats going on...

As you might know, I am doing my MSc. in The Netherlands, at the Delft University of Technology. Last year I found out that our faculty has several agreements with universities all around the world regarding exchange programs. Well, that naturally caught my attention so I started thinking about going further abroad for another semester. I have decided to go to Asia, because Europe does not make sense for me and I did not feel like going to the USA or another English-speaking country. Moreover, the Asian culture is so different from Europe that any experience with it might be very valuable. There were basically three choices — Harbin in China, Tokyo in Japan and Seoul in Korea. Because Harbin was only for two months and Japan is quite expensive and maybe a little too <del>weird</del> different, I have decided to come to KAIST Business School in Seoul, which is a MBA oriented part of the otherwise technically oriented KAIST university in Daejeon.

The application and organization was a bit of a struggle, but luckily everything worked out fine and I was admitted to the Fall 2011 Exchange program. I am focusing mainly at Information and Media MBA, which is in line with my planned master thesis direction. I will spend 4 months here and then come back to Delft to start working on my master thesis. So, that's why I am here and not in Europe. Simple, right...]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>17</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-09 13:25:57</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-09 04:25:57</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>explanation</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1315542357]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title></title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/10/31/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 16:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=31</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="aligncenter" title="Bukhansan National Park" src="http://tong.visitkorea.or.kr/cms/resource/03/802503_image2_1.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" />
<blockquote>If your energy begins to flag, consider taking a swig of the Korean hiker’s friend: pine-needle <em>soju </em>(local vodka-like brew). One mouthful should be enough to help you make it to the top. Well, that’s what Koreans claim anyway.</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:right;">-Lonely Planet guide <a title="Lonely Planet — Bukhansan National park" href="http://www.lonelyplanet.com/south-korea/gyeonggi-do/bukhansan-national-park">entry</a> for Bukhansan National Park</p>
Yep, that's where we go tomorrow!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>31</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-10 01:20:56</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-09 16:20:56</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>31</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-quote"><![CDATA[Quote]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1315585257]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>A fortnight</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/13/a-fortnight/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=37</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Splendid! Two awesome weeks that feel like at least a month. Last week the classes have (finally) started. In the first half of the semester I am taking 4 classes — two "real" (Growth Strategy and Valuation of IT Media Business) and two "exchange" (Korean for Foreigners I and Korean Business and Culture). This should keep me relatively busy, but still leave some time for fun and traveling and other things exchange students usually do. The class schedule here is quite interesting. Classes are only 80 minutes long, and there are usually two each weak (Mon+Wed or Tue+Thu). Out of class work seems to be less extensive than in Delft so in general the workload might be lower. However, it has still been only a week, so I don't want to make premature conclusions.

I have to say that I am more than happy with my choice of subjects. I picked the courses so they would support my current direction, because I did not want to spend this semester doing meaningless courses just to bring some ECTS home.

[caption id="attachment_39" align="aligncenter" width="500" caption="Tha hikin&#039; gang"]<a style="text-decoration:underline;font-family:'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;" href="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/p1000274.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-39" style="background-image:initial;background-attachment:initial;background-color:#eeeeee;margin-top:.4em;border-color:initial;border-style:initial;" title="Tha gang" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/p1000274.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a>[/caption]

Enough of school, though. As announced earlier, on Saturday we went to the Bukhansan National Park for some hiking. Well, Korean hiking is certainly different from the European. It all started with about 300m of altitude of stairs. Yes, steep stairs like in a mall. On the left from the stairs there was a wall, on the right there was a fence and a military area with forbidden access. Fun fun fun. Unfortunately, thanks to all the smog, the view on Seoul was not very god either, so we just had to keep climbing up.

[caption id="attachment_42" align="aligncenter" width="333" caption="Stairway To Heaven"]<a href="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/p1000296.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-42" title="Stairway To Heaven" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/p1000296.jpg?w=200" alt="" width="333" height="500" /></a>[/caption]

Funny thing about this national park is that since it is close to some military facility, every visitor has to fill out a entry form and gets a badge. In the form there is a list of rules such as "Photographs can be takes only at designated spots" and "No alcoholic beverages can be consumed inside the park" etc. Sounds like a exciting trip, right. Well, so we kept climbing until we got to the top. There was a small plain with a lot of Koreans, that were having lunch, and few security guards that were taking care that no one is breaking the aforementioned rules.
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/p1000286.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-40" title="Badge" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/p1000286.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
The rest of the trip fortunately went better. Even though the whole was basically between the fence and the wall, the nature around was more interesting and once we even reached some kind of a pine groove that allowed us to walk next to the stairs like real hikers. Yeah!

[caption id="attachment_43" align="aligncenter" width="5000" caption="Lunching at the top"]<a href="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/p1000314.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-43 " title="Lunching at the top" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/p1000314.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="5000" height="333" /></a>[/caption]

In the evening we were planning to go clubbing to Gangnam's Club Eden. Eden is supposed to be the biggest/most famous/bestest club in Seoul / Korea / Asia / World / Universe, so we wanted to experience it as well. Our plan did not quite work out, because we ended up in Itaewon in Club Volume, where we did not have to pay the cover to get in. Well, the party was nice, even though I liked the Cocoon Club a little more. From unknown reasons I prefer mostly Korean clubs, because otherwise I feel like in some European city. Since Itaewon is quite and international part of Seoul, the club was full of intl's, including a Dutch girl from R'dam, who's parents were living in Prague. After coming home at 7am we had a quick breakfast with Rik and Lauriane at the roof of our dorms and then off to bed for 9 hours of well deserved sleep. It's quite funny that I basically went to bed in European time, since 7am here is 12pm in Europe.

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="500" caption="Keep dancing till the world ends..."]<img title="Keep dancing till the world ends..." src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/s720x720/314638_10150296081221297_571766296_8365367_1918190991_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="383" />[/caption]

Since I'm tired now, I'll leave the Karaoke episode description for some other time...]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>37</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-13 01:48:46</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-12 16:48:46</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>a-fortnight</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1315846129]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>K-POP!</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/13/k-pop/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 06:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=57</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><strong>K-pop</strong> (an abbreviation of Koreanpop or Korean popular music) is a musical genre consisting of electropop, hip hop, pop, rock, and R&amp;B music originating in South Korea. In addition to music, K-pop has grown into a popular subculture among teenagers and young adults around the world, resulting in widespread interest in the fashion and style of Korean idol groups and singers</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:right;">—<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K-pop">Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Words are not enough to describe it. You just have to see it...so sit back, relax and enjoy the awesome weirdness/weird awesomeness of K-POP...</p>

<h1 style="text-align:left;">T-ara — Roly Poly</h1>
<p style="text-align:left;">[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afwK0Mv0IsY]</p>

<h1 style="text-align:left;">SNSD — Gee</h1>
[youtube=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AqOexfWm4Ds]
<h1>Hyori Lee - U Go Girl</h1>
[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WEitb0zF-Yc]

<em>(Yes, there are male singers as well, however, I really don't feel like posting their videos on my blog)</em>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>57</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-13 15:43:26</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-13 06:43:26</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>k-pop</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1315896208]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Ma&#039; fellaz in da hood</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/15/ma-fellaz-in-da-hood/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 05:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=65</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Apparently, I am not the only exchange student @ KAIST that is blogging. For more reading pleasure, here I introduce my other blogging friends. However, they blog in their native language, so just use <del>the force</del> Google Translate.
<ul>
	<li><strong>Karin:</strong> <a href="http://seoulong.wordpress.com/">http://seoulong.wordpress.com/</a></li>
	<li><strong>Ada:</strong> <a href="http://jeonhwon.blogspot.com/">http://jeonhwon.blogspot.com/</a></li>
	<li><strong>Thomas:</strong> <a href="http://koreasdiary.blogspot.com/">http://koreasdiary.blogspot.com/</a></li>
</ul>
Enjoy!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>65</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-15 14:43:37</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-15 05:43:37</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>ma-fellaz-in-da-hood</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316065418]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_mess</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Ma' fellaz in da hood: http://wp.me/p1OL2f-13]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>4</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Thomas]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>thomas_sabatier@orange.fr</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://koreasdiary.blogspot.com/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>137.68.54.50</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2011-09-15 20:58:56</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2011-09-15 11:58:56</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[hey ! Nice blog :) Actually I changed the URL of mine, and by the way the language... No more google translate \o/]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1316087937.0898";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316149011]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1316149011.8406";s:7:"message";s:45:"swaycz changed the comment status to approved";s:5:"event";s:15:"status-approved";s:4:"user";s:6:"swaycz";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>5</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Thomas]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>thomas_sabatier@orange.fr</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://koreasdiary.blogspot.com/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>137.68.54.50</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2011-09-15 20:59:24</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2011-09-15 11:59:24</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[And the link : http://koreasdiary.blogspot.com/]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>4</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1316087964.9984";s:7:"message";s:35:"Akismet caught this comment as spam";s:5:"event";s:10:"check-spam";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1316149086.6368";s:7:"message";s:40:"swaycz reported this comment as not spam";s:5:"event";s:10:"report-ham";s:4:"user";s:6:"swaycz";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_user_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_user</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[swaycz]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316149092]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:14:"1316149092.238";s:7:"message";s:45:"swaycz changed the comment status to approved";s:5:"event";s:15:"status-approved";s:4:"user";s:6:"swaycz";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Study time again</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/15/study-time-again/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 10:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=71</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Assignments, cases, tests, here we go again...

[caption id="attachment_72" align="aligncenter" width="584" caption="Emerging Nokia? and other interesting stories"]<a href="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/study.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-72" title="Emerging Nokia? and other interesting stories" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/study.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="389" /></a>[/caption] ]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>71</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-15 19:08:18</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-15 10:08:18</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>study-time-again</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-image"><![CDATA[Image]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316081298]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_mess</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Study time again:]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Eden or Hell</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/16/eden-or-hell/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 07:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=77</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>If Eden looks like Club Eden, than I really don't know what religion is for...it was more like Hell...</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>77</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-16 16:47:46</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-16 07:47:46</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>eden-or-hell</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-quote"><![CDATA[Quote]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316159266]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The best city tour ever and the tower of love</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/17/the-best-city-tour-ever-and-the-tower-of-love/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 16:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=85</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[City tour. We have all been there. Unknown city or place, a bus full of people, boring commentary (stupid jokes included). Well, since we are not only students, but also tourists here, we have decided to give it a go. Well, Karin has decided and few of us joined her. We had nothing to do anyway, since it was Chuseok Monday and most places were closed. The plan was to take the <a title="Seoul City Bus" href="http://en.seoulcitybus.com/" target="_blank">night tour</a>, which is a 1:30h bus tour through the Seoul city center, including the N Seoul Tower. And the plan failed big time. Now we know that it can take more than a hour to get from our campus to the Gwanghwamun station. Yes, despite our heroic effort and a subway transfer sprint, we missed the bus. Well, both of them, actually — <a title="Enter Shikari - OK, Time For Plan B" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bfAijSveeoY">OK, Time For Plan B</a>. At least the neighborhood was nice.

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="550" caption="Gwanghwamun station neighborhood (via Karin)"]<img class=" " title="Gwanghwamun station neighborhood" src="http://seoulong.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/img_1141.jpg" alt="" width="550" />[/caption]

We saw a Chuseok celebration with some acrobats/dancers, which was awesome. Since we were quite close to the "cozy part of Seoul", which we discovered after our "hiking" trip, we decided to go there and try find some nice place to get food and drinks. That proved to be quite difficult, because nearly all places were either closed because of Chuseok or were closing because it was already around 9:30pm. Eventually we found a nice place, where we got delicious dumplings. Huge and delicious. They are filled with minced meat and some veggies, and fill you up immediately. And they are not spicy!

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="550" caption="Chuseok celebration (via Karin)"]<img class=" " title="Chuseok celebration" src="http://seoulong.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/img_1154.jpg" alt="" width="550" />[/caption]

Tuesday was more exciting. Not only the shops and restaurants were open again, but we also decided to go to the N Seoul Tower, which is, for unknown reasons, portrayed as a love tower. Supposedly, the Namsan Mountain, where the tower is located is some kind of a "first love" place. Some say, that you should go there with your first love and put a lock with some personal message on the fence there. The fence is just packed with locks, and they even have to take some away every year, otherwise the whole thing would be too heavy and there would not be any place for another firstlovers.

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="375" caption="N Seoul Tower — via flickr"]<img title="N Seoul Tower" src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1306/851500946_e1abf7512e.jpg" alt="" width="375" height="500" />[/caption]

I was quite surprised by the number of people around the tower. I honestly expected that it would be nearly deserted place, but the park around the tower was packed with people, mostly Koreans. Seems like Namsan is a favorite place to hang out in Seoul. Anyway, the view was terrific and we even managed to locate our campus. Or at least the black spot where the campus was supposed to be. Guess we should have told someone to light a bonfire at the roof for better identification.

Anyway, sometimes it is nice to be a tourist, especially when you know the place a little. There are still thousands of places in Seoul that are worth visiting, from the Dongdaemun market to the War Museum. We also want to visit the DMZ and some other places in Korea, of course. But we'll see, school is getting more and more intensive and even though this is an exchange, one has to work as well.

N.B.: Photos shamelessly stolen from <a href="http://seoulong.wordpress.com">Karin</a>. Thanks!:)]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>85</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-17 01:20:17</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-16 16:20:17</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-best-city-tour-ever-and-the-tower-of-love</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316190018]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>6</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[seoulong]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>karrenfeldt@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://seoulong.wordpress.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>137.68.54.34</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2011-09-18 10:51:10</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2011-09-18 01:51:10</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Any time Honza! :)]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>25179993</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1316310670.7501";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:8:"seoulong";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316311988]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1316311989.0027";s:7:"message";s:45:"swaycz changed the comment status to approved";s:5:"event";s:15:"status-approved";s:4:"user";s:6:"swaycz";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Seoul Subway Song (서울 지하철 노래)</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/18/seoul-subway-song-%ec%84%9c%ec%9a%b8-%ec%a7%80%ed%95%98%ec%b2%a0-%eb%85%b8%eb%9e%98/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 04:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=95</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Simply brilliant...to explain it a little, the subway in Seoul plays several jingles before stations depending on which line you can transfer to. This song is based on one of them (it's not the best jingle, though:))

[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tWcDTEaATxI] ]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>95</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-18 13:54:54</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-18 04:54:54</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>seoul-subway-song-%ec%84%9c%ec%9a%b8-%ec%a7%80%ed%95%98%ec%b2%a0-%eb%85%b8%eb%9e%98</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316321695]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>20</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Culinary adventures I. | S(e)oul eXchange]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=256</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>76.74.248.213</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2011-10-22 13:55:11</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2011-10-22 04:55:11</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[...] Yesterday I found this song by the same guy who did the Seoul Subway Song (Michael Aronson aka 마익흘). 김밥 (kimbap) is a Korean dish, that comprises 김 (kim, [...] ]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1319259352.1586";s:7:"message";s:45:"swaycz changed the comment status to approved";s:5:"event";s:15:"status-approved";s:4:"user";s:6:"swaycz";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1319259351]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1319259311.3608";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Sick-o</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/19/sick-o/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 01:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=98</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Well, there it goes...the changing weather, aircon and perhaps also my stupidity caused that my f-ed up immunity eventually gave up and now I'm sick...sore throat + muscles, yay! Hope it gets better soon...]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>98</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-19 10:07:59</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-19 01:07:59</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>sick-o</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-aside"><![CDATA[Aside]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316394481]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Pivo - Beer - 맥주</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/20/pivo-beer-%eb%a7%a5%ec%a3%bc/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 04:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=101</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[A little piece of my homeland as found in Korea, captured with my phone. As usual, it's all about the beer...

[caption id="attachment_102" align="aligncenter" width="550" caption="Gambrinus Premium — 2500KRW in 7/11"]<a href="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/pic-0169-e1316492029395.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-102 " title="Gambrinus Premium — 2500KRW in 7/11" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/pic-0169-e1316492098862.jpg" alt="" width="550" /></a>[/caption]

[caption id="attachment_103" align="aligncenter" width="550" caption="Gambrinus Premium — &quot;Skvělá cena&quot;"]<a href="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/pic-0174-e1316491717687.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-103" title="Gambrinus Premium — &quot;Skvělá cena&quot;" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/pic-0174-e1316491717687.jpg" alt="" width="550" height="412" /></a>[/caption]

[caption id="attachment_104" align="aligncenter" width="550" caption="&quot;Pivo&quot; Bar"]<a href="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/pic-0178-e1316491467543.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-104" title="&quot;Pivo&quot; Bar" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/pic-0178-e1316491467543.jpg" alt="" width="550" height="620" /></a>[/caption] ]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>101</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-20 13:18:03</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-20 04:18:03</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>pivo-beer-%eb%a7%a5%ec%a3%bc</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-gallery"><![CDATA[Gallery]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316492283]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Autumn in Seoul</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/24/autumn-in-seoul/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2011 12:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=114</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[No, wait, sorry, it's still summer...the weather is going quite crazy. Long pants, short pants, sweatshirt, t-shirt, shirt, you never know what to wear. I was quite happy that the we finally got the real autumn weather, when t-shirt is still OK but sweatshirt is fine as well, however, today the weather proved me wrong, because it is around 25°C again. Well, that does not really help me not feel sick

Apart from the crazy weather, the school is getting more and more intense as well. Assignments, presentations, here we go. On top of that, I still have to finish our report from Kenya (duh!) and work on a project for one course in Delft. And have fun, right:) Talking about schoolwork. Almost every course has some group project associated to it, which is quite similar to Delft. The only difference is, that the groups here are usually selected by teachers, so you can't really influence the team composition. For increased variety and "multiculturality" exchange students are in most cases assigned to different groups, which is fine, because you at least get the chance to see how Korean groupwork works (?). And that is the problem. Why? Let me explain something about Korea first.

The Korean culture is very much based on hierarchy and status. Are you older? You are superior. Do you have a better job than me? You are superior. Are you a young foreign student? Go screw yourself. Ok, that is a little exaggerated. The point is that the group dynamics are soooo different compared to Europe, and The Netherlands in particular. Over there, all the group members are equal. You have something to say? Then go for it. If it's crap we will tell you, never mind. All the little fights inside the group are expected and even induced, because they lead to a better result. In Korea, however, the discussion is much more "civilized". Everybody is so respectful, that they are not able to criticize other's ideas. Every idea is good, only some are better. And every idea has to be approved by the eldest person in the group, otherwise it is not considered acceptable. I find this rather annoying, because I am used to "say stuff". Throwing ideas, comments, feedback, criticism at others, and letting them do the same. Here it is not possible. Not only that criticizing older people is not acceptable, but since I am usually the youngest in the group, no one expects me to do so.

I know that now you might think how unadaptable I am, but it is really hard to switch to a completely different behavior. I am trying, trust me. Thinking twice before saying something and trying to obey the rules they have. I am in fact happy about this experience. I think it will really help me in dealing with people, because until now, I always had the advantage of the home environment and this is the second time (after Kenya) I am an alien in a completely different cultural environment.

And in Korea I am literally an Alien — I have finally received my Alien Registration Card, which is quite essential if you want to do something here. Not only you need it to open a bank account or to get a mobile phone, but it also serves as a multientry visa, so you don't have to pay additional $50 when you want to go to China or Japan and then come back.

Since I was sick and I had stuff to do, last week was quite dull. The highlight was Mark's B-Day party, which started with a pre-game at the 7th floor (soju + beer) and then continued in Hongdae in Cocoon. It was fun, even though some people suffered from a premature ending and went back to the dorms before we reached the club. I managed to retain my sobriety, so the morning was pretty acceptable.

Some pictures from Marc:
[slideshow]

However, I hope that the true highlight, the summit, the peak, the apex of this week is still ahead, because tomorrow, my friends, tomorrow we are going to conquer the LOTTE WORLD!

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="550" caption="Lotte World (source: http://triptokorea.com)"]<img class=" " title="Lotte World" src="http://english.triptokorea.com/english/UserFiles/Image/Special%20Tour/Activity/Lotte%20World2.jpg" alt="" width="550" />[/caption]

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="550" caption="Lotte World (source: http://themeparkguy.com)"]<img class=" " title="Lotte World — Rollercoaster" src="http://www.thethemeparkguy.com/filestore/themepark/lotte-world/285/lotte-world-16-big.jpg" alt="Lotte World — Rollercoaster" width="550" />[/caption] ]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>114</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-24 21:18:34</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-24 12:18:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>autumn-in-seoul</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1316866716]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_mess</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Autumn in Seoul: http://wp.me/p1OL2f-1Q]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Finally mobile</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/26/finally-mobile/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 12:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=134</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[As pathetic as it might sound, in a country with mobile phone penetration of almost 99%, until today, I was offline. Well, I had my EU phone, which perfectly works here (it's a Samsung, btw.), but roaming is quite expensive for everyday use, so I wanted to get a Korean phone. Before coming here, my good friend Roman gave me the phone he used while he was on exchange here, so I just needed to get it registered on my Alien ID. Therefore, when our uni arranged some phones for us, I politely declined the offer, thinking that I will simply register the phone I already had.

Now you might think <em>"Registered? What do you mean?"</em> or simply <em>"WTF, dude?"</em>, but bureaucracy rules Korea, and <strong>every</strong> Korean phone needs to be registered with their Ministry of Telecommunications or something like that. And registered means that the S/N of the phone is paired with the SSN of the owner. Do you also feel a little bit of 1984? Because of that, some phones do not even have SIM cards, but function merely on this registration basis with regular pre-paid plan.

Unfortunately, Roman forgot to <strong>deregister</strong> his phone before leaving Korea, what I found our last week. And since his Alien ID has already expired, the phone is basically a useless piece of ancient electronics unless he comes here and deregisters it.

Since everything is easier when you speak Korean, I took my buddy <strong>Hojoong</strong> with me and went phoneshopping. Despite his negotiation efforts, all the offers were too expensive for me. I really don't need to buy another phone, 감사합니다 (<em>kamsahamnida)</em>. Fortunately, thanks to <strong>Jin</strong> from the KBS International Center, I managed to contact the company that gave other students the phone deal (which is much cheaper, since they only rent the phone instead of buying it) and today, their guy came to KAIST and handed me my brand new Korean phone. Awesome!

[caption id="attachment_135" align="aligncenter" width="550" caption="My collection of Korean phones (LTR) — Samsung SGH-i600, Anycall (Samsung) SCH-C320, Ever (KT Tech) EV-W450"]<a href="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/phones.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-135" title="Korean phones collection" src="http://soulexchange.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/phones.jpg" alt="" width="550" height="412" /></a>[/caption]

The phone is quite cool actually. It is a Ever (KT Tech) EV-W450 phone, that is manufactured exclusively for KT Telecom (hence, KT Tech). It is a "slider", which is currently the most popular kind of phone, apart from touchscreen smartphones, and it is a regular <em>featurephone</em>, so it has Bluetooth and other useful thingies, however, it lacks WiFi or other internet connectivity. And it has, wait for it, Mobile TV a.k.a. DMB! I can watch gameshows and soap operas 24/7, for free! Frankly, I think I won't use it even once, but whatever. Who can say he has a TV in his phone, right:)]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>134</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-26 21:19:05</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-26 12:19:05</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>finally-mobile</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1317039547]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Lotte World...</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/29/lotte-world/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 13:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=142</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>...a place where your dreams come true and where unsuccessful Russian ballet dancers perform in ridiculous costumes.</em>

Lotte World is a theme park. According to Koreans, it is the biggest indoor theme park in Asia, which does not surprise me, because they are simply obsessed with superiority. As one presenter told us today during the Korean Business and Culture lecture, Koreans do not have fast food, they have <em>faster</em> food. The park is located in Gangnam-gu (강남구), close the the Olympic Park. It has two parts — one big hall and the Magic Island, that is literally an island with a castle. Since this castle also dominates the Lotte World logo, when you see it, you can't stop wondering "Hmm, this seems familiar!". A little hint — Disney.

I won't spend time describing the park, since it is a typical theme park with rollercoasters, merry-go-rounds, thrill rides, water rides, big looping thingie, free fall tower, lots of junk food and little screaming kids. The hall with a indoor rollercoaster is cool, especially because they managed to squeeze a lopping inside it. The sightseeing baloon ride around the hall was also fun — a nice way to calm down after the endorphin and adrenaline shots on the rollercoaster. The best attractions were on the Magic Island, though — Gyro Swing and Atlantic Adventure really made my day. The first one is a giant pendulum with a rotating platform at the end, while the latter is a rollercoaster with a launch start and few steep drops.

It was a nice day, I have to admit. Theme park is exactly the kind of activity that allows you to shut down your brain and just enjoy the thrill. You are screaming like a little kid, eating hamburgers for both breakfast and lunch and just having a good time. It is even better when you do it with a group of friends, because a shared experience is always better:)

I took quite a lot of pictures, so there is a selection of the best/most interesting ones.

[slideshow]

Btw. there was one thing that really surprised me. LW was full of couples. That's not that surprising, right, but these couples were in many cases wearing the same clothes, or at least t-shirts/sweatshirts. I can't imagine that a European guy would do something like that. Not talking about the headbands with ears that both girls and guys were wearing. I guess that's simply Korea.

Oh yeah, I nearly forgot the Russian thing. Apparently, some Russian/Ukrainian dancers are working in LW as, well, dancers and performers. It was quite surprising to see white people performing in a Korean theme park, but I guess there is simply a limited market for ballet dancers in Europe:)]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>142</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-29 22:04:12</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-29 13:04:12</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>lotte-world</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1317301455]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Apology to Korean culture</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/30/apology-to-korean-culture/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 17:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=160</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I just realized that in my previous post about the group work here I might have been too European, too mean and self-centered. And that is bad. I greatly admire the respect Koreans show to each other, and I am convinced, that European, or Western culture has a lot to learn from them. We will never be able to be like Koreans, and at the same time, Koreans will never be like us, however, both cultures should try to exchange the positive aspects, because that would bring them closer. Consider this an apology to all my groupmates that might have been offended by my "Westernity" — I'll to conform and absorb instead of fighting with the culture.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>160</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-30 02:26:42</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-29 17:26:42</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>apology-to-korean-culture</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-aside"><![CDATA[Aside]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1317317202]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_fb</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>햄버가마요</title>
		<link>http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/2011/09/30/%ed%96%84%eb%b2%84%ea%b0%80%eb%a7%88%ec%9a%94/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 09:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swaycz</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulexchange.wordpress.com/?p=163</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>When you say "hamburgermayo" with proper English accent, you get nothing. However, when you say 햄버가마요주세요 (hembeokamayochuseyo), you get one hamburgermayo and a smile. Welcome to Korea:)</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>163</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-30 18:12:59</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-30 09:12:59</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>%ed%96%84%eb%b2%84%ea%b0%80%eb%a7%88%ec%9a%94</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_format" nicename="post-format-quote"><![CDATA[Quote]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="stuff"><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9130441]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1317373979]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
